Edwin Espinoza

(760) 215-0969 • espined48@gmail.com • edwin-espinoza.com

Professional Summary

Web developers with experience building RESTful application. Many different skills from basic LAMP stack to MEAN stack. Created full application user authentication using passport and full database support using MongoDB. Familiar with many common JavaScript libraries.

Education

Humboldt State University - Arcata, CA

Bachelor's Degree: 2020

- B.S. Computer Science
- Applied Mathematics Minor

Work History

General Tutor (middle school and high school), 08/2018 to 06/2020 Humboldt State University – Arcata, CA

- I would drive to different school sites that have TRIO Talent Search students.
- Be able to work without supervision and help students with math.
- Ran a coding club at one of the local middle schools.
- Held structured meetings to discuss STEM summer programs to get students interested in STEM fields, as well as developed lessons and lesson plans for students.

Computer Science Tutor, 01/2019 to 05/2020 Humboldt State University – Arcata, CA

- Helped university students with their assignments and understanding of computer science concepts.
- Responsible for tracking student usage of tutoring services, and creating a friendly and studious environment for students to work in.

Math Tutor, 06/2016 to 08/2018

Palomar Community College District – San Marcos, CA

- I would make appointments with students for up to an hour to help the students with their math problems.
- I had to learn and understand the many different backgrounds and cultures students came from to help understand their learning styles.
- I also had to manage time with the students, as well as watch for walk-in students who did not have appointments.

References

Dr. Richard Sauerheber: Co-worker, Tutor, Researcher, Ph.D. Chemistry from University of CA, San Diego

Phone: (760) 744-1150 x2448E-mail: rsauerheber@palomar.edu

Dr. Bori Mazzag: Supervisor, Chair of Mathematics & Computer Science Ph.D. Applied Mathematics from University of CA, Davis

• Phone: (707) 826-4952

• E-mail: borim@humboldt.edu

Rose Sita Francia: Supervisor, M.A. in Educational Leadership, TRIO Talent Search Director and Collaboration Lead

• Phone: (707) 826-4791

• E-mail: <u>rose.francia@humboldt.edu</u>